Province of St. John the Baptist Franciscans records, 1868-1978 (bulk 1906-1965)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series XII: FatherEmanuel Trockur, 1924-1977
  - Biographical Material, 1963-1970
    - Tributes including his Golden Jubilee. (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Oral History Interviews, University of Utah. August 1967, September 1970 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Dedication of St. Joseph Church, Colfax, Ill., Father Emanuel, Chaplain. April 30, 1963 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Trip to Europe. September 1966 (Box 47, Folder 8-9)
    - Trip to Europe: Postcards and brochures. September 1966 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1924-1977
    - Church Correspondence. 1924-1975 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence. 1935-1976 (Box 48, Folder 2-4)
    - Requests for information, etc. 1933-1975 (Box 48, Folder 5-9)
    - Family Correspondence. (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Casey, Father Edgar. 1929, 1936-1938, 1956-1966 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Frisbie, Charlotte. 1967-1977 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Glass, Rose. 1931-1969 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Golden, Gertrude. 1954-1960 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      Also includes a letter from Father Celestine to Gertrude Golden, 1936.
    - Gray, Anne. 1953-1958 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Hailman, H. V. 1957-1958 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Hodge, William H. 1962-1964 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Karl, W. A. 1962-1963 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Knapp, Arline H. 1953-1954 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Kowalski, Bishop Rembert C.: Biographical material. (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Kowalski, Bishop Rembert C.: Correspondence. 1928-1971 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Long, Paul V. 1964-1968 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Miller, Harry E. "Two Gun." 1946-1947 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Mower, Mrs. Jack and St. Theresa Guild. 1953-1962 (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - Reidy, E. T. 1960-1975 (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - Rom, Rod. 1968-1970 (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - University of Arizona. 1960-1966 (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - Wigglesworth, Dr. Albert and Family. 1958-1974 (Box 49, Folder 19)
    - Witzmann, Father Byron. 1958-1965 (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - Wuest, Father John B., editor of The Provincial Chronicle. 1938-1943 (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - Writings and Speeches, 1929-1963
    - Articles: "History of the Ranch," (St. Michaels Mission). (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Articles: "Work of the Navajo Missionaries to Date," (proposed article). 1936 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Articles: "With the Franciscans," St. Anthony Messenger. June-July 1948 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Various typescripts. (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Various published articles. (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Baccalaureate speeches. 1929-1952 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Essays. (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Invocations. (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Sermons (?). (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Franciscan Lay Missionary Summer Program: "Navajo Culture," talks. (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Various talks. (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Material for articles. (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Retreat Papers: Waterflow and Roswell. 1954, 1955 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Retreat Papers: White Sisters Conference. 1953-1963 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Retreat Papers: Miscellaneous. (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Personal Interests, 1933-1946
    - Indian Education. (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Navajo Citizenship, Right to Vote. (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Navajo Culture, Religion, Customs. (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Navaho Language. (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Navajo Language Related to Tenah Indians of Alaska. (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - "Navaho Problem." (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Peyote. (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Hopi Mission. (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Hubbell Family and Trading Post: Miscellaneous material. (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Mike Kirk and Trading Post. (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Tekakwitha: Correspondence. 1933-1946 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Tekakwitha: Printed material, clippings. (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Massacre Cave and Canyon del Muerto. (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - General Philosophy and Ethics. (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Catholicism, Theology, Religious Education. (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, Fragments, etc. (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Confraternity of Christian Doctrine, 1941-1962
    - Correspondence: General. 1941-1962 (Box 52, Folder 1-3)
    - Correspondence: Grigsby, Mary D. 1954-1959 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Pflaum, George A., Publisher. 1949-1959 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Eileen, Sister Mary. 1957-1958, 1960 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Letters to pastors. 1942-1961 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Reports. 1942-1960 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Catechetical Sunday. (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - 1st Regional Congress, Province of Santa Fe, Santa Fe, New Mexico. October 26-28, 1948 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - 2nd Regional Congress, Province of Santa Fe, El, Paso, Texas. April 10-12, 1951 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - 3rd Regional Congress, Province of Santa Fe, Albuquerque, New Mexico. October 2-4, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - 4th Regional Congress, Province of Santa Fe, El Paso, Texas. October 17-20, 1957 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - 9th National Catechetical Congress, Chicago, Illinois. November 7-11, 1951 (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - 10th National Catechetical Congress, Buffalo, New York. September 26-30, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Various Congresses. 1946-1961 (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous notes by Father Emanuel. (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - Lists of Archdiocesan and Diocesan Directors. 1955-1959 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Annual Meetings of Archdiocesan and Diocesan Directors. 1955-1959 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Lay Committee Annual Meetings. 1955-1959 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - "Released Time," miscellaneous material. (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Assorted publications, brochures, newsletters, manuals, etc. (Box 53, Folder 5-6)
- Series XIII: Robert L. Wilken's Anselm Weber, O. F.M.: Missionary to the Navaho, 1898-1921, Bruce Publishing Company, 1955, 1949-1973
  - Various Correspondence. 1949-1952 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Tucker, Father Emanuel. 1951-1973 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Adams, Jewel. 1951-1952 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Orders. 1954-1966 (Box 54, Folder 4)
- Series XIV: Oversize Material, 1906-1973
  - St. Michaels Precinct, Apache County, Arizona, Tally List. 1906, 1908 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - St. Michaels Precinct, Apache County, Arizona, Poll List. 1914 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Townsite of Navajo: maps and photograph. (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - St. Michaels Mission: Financial records. July 1906-August 1916 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - The 47th Star Edition of the McKinley County Republican, Gallup, New Mexico. September 1912 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Navajo and Zuni Reservation, Navajo District: Preliminary Base Map, U. S. Soil Conservation Service. April 15, 1936 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Oversize Clipping: "Cry for Help from the Proud Navajo," Life. January 5, 1968 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Oversize Clipping: "Arizona Ambassadors," St. John's Indian School, Komatke, Arizona, Our Sunday Visitor, National Catholic Weekly. May 19, 1968 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - "Navajo Allotments in Arizona," Peterson and Simington locations (3 original drawings). May 1, 1914 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Township Plats. (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Maps. (Box 55, Folder 9)
    Navajo Reservation Road Mileage Map, 1950
    Navajo, Hopi and Zuni Indian Reservations, no date
    Navajo Indian Reservation and Adjacent Areas, July 1973 (2 copies)
    Indian and Mexican Missions in the Southwest, March 1943
    Part of Map of Expedition of Fathers Domingues and Escalante, 1776 (photostatic copy)
    Navajo Country, Arizona, New Mexico and Utah, 1920
  - Miscellaneous Maps. (Box 55, Folder 10)
    U. S. General Land Office Map, Territory of New Mexico, 1909
    New Mexico Township Map, no date
    Clason's Guide to Map of New Mexico, 1916
    Clason's Guide to Map of New Mexico, 1919 (with notes)
  - U. S. Department of Interior Map: Arizona, compiled by Daniel P. O'Hare. 1921 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Rand-McNally Map: Arizona. 1913 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - U. S. Forest Service Map: Zuni National Forest, parts 1-2. 1909 (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - U. S. Forest Service Map: Zuni National Forest, part 1. 1910 (Box 55, Folder 12)